本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
Be sure you make yourself heard!
声出してけよ
Yessir!
よしゃあ
Yeah!
Hm... Karasuno definitely seems different.
烏野雰囲気が違うね
Excuse us!
すんません
Oh?
Well, well...
これはこれは
If it isn't Tobio, the little boy I gave a good whipping the last time we met.
前回俺にこてんぱんにやられた飛雄ちゃんじゃないですか
We've come to win this time.
今回は勝ちに来ました
I definitively put you in your place last time!
お前は前回完膚なきまでに凹ましたからな
残すはウシワカ野郎ただ一人
All that's left is that bastard, Ushiwaka!
I will have you stand aside again, Tobio!
今回も退いてもらうぜ飛雄
思い知たか
Take that!
Is he really a third-year?
こいつこれで高３か
It's way too early to let Oikawa get to him.
あいつ手玉に取られんの早すぎだろ
Hey.
なぁおい
Yes?
烏野に女の子増えてる
Karasuno's got another girl.
Sorry, Yachi!
谷地さんごめん
カワイイ系
She's a cutie.
Here.
そすねこの悔しさは何でしょうか
Yeah. I wonder why I'm so frustrated by that.
All right.
よしゃ
すみません
Pardon me.
Could you get that?
取てください
Damn it! Look out!
危ない
Fly
Holy crap...
お強い
ほらよ
Here.
Thanks...
どうも
くそダメだた
Damn, it didn't work.
Karasuno's guard is too strong.
烏野ガドかてぇ
You're such a showoff, Yahaba.
矢巾さんてホントチャラいすね
Come on! We're about to start warming up!
ほらささとウオムアプやるぞ
Ow.
痛
A-Are you okay?
大丈夫すか
Kageyama?
影山
Huh?
青城にあんな奴いたけ
Was that guy on Seijou's team before?
Dunno.
キャプテン
Captains.
Let's have a good match.
お願いします/お願いします
Episode Twenty:
Sweep Clear
I guess you're okay now.
体は大丈夫なんだ
Yeah, thanks.
ああどうも
I got to rest a while, so I'm actually full of energy.
長く休んでむしろ元気だ
Oh, really?
マジですか
You seem like you've aged a bit, Sawamura.
なんか澤村くん
貫禄ついたんじゃない
These past four months...
この四ヶ月
Another penalty?
またペナルティ
You guys must love those.
好きなのかな
Hey, hey, hey! You on a break?
ヘイヘイヘイ休憩中
Then let's practice!
じゃ練習しようぜ
I've been whipped into shape by some other goons.
Hey, hey, hey!
けこうな曲者達に揉まれてきたんでね
Dunno what you're talking about, but good job.
よくわかんないけどお疲れ
Tails is Aoba Jousai, heads is Karasuno.
裏が青葉城西
表が烏野です
We'll receive first.
先レシブで
Then we'll serve first.
じゃあサブで
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
Line up!
整列
We're gonna win this match.
この試合
勝つのは俺達だ
Yeah.
お願いします
Let's have a good match!
Hey! I made it in time.
おす間に合た
Hey.
よう午前の和久南戦けこうな死闘だたぞ
The Waku South match in the morning was pretty brutal.
Really? I wish I'd been able to see it.
そかぁ見たかたな
Huh?
Heya! I'm Tanaka Ryuunosuke's big sister!
ども田中龍之介の姉です
Hi!
どもす
She looks just like him.
田中の姉似てる
They got all the way to the semis, huh?
準決勝まで来ちまたな
Yeah.
This is the semi-finals?
これが準決勝
Huh? That means...
えてことは
Jouzenji
Karasuno
Ougi Business
Waku South
Shirato
Date Tech
Jouzenji
Karasuno
Ougi Business
Waku South
Shirato
Date Tech
Winner
Wait. So if they win this one and the next one,
they're going to nationals?! Isn't that awesome?!
これと次も勝てば全国行きてこと
すごくない
Well, only if they beat the next two powerful schools.
まあ超強敵２校を倒したらだけどな
This will be the third time our
current team has faced Karasuno.
このチムで烏野と戦うのはこれが３度目だ
They've surprised us every time.
戦う度烏野にはいつも驚かされてきた
I'm sure things won't go smoothly this time, either.
たぶん今回も一筋縄ではいかないだろう
But if we keep our cool, victory will come naturally.
だが落ち着いて戦えば
自ずと勝利は見えてくる
Go play to the best of your abilities.
精一杯戦てきなさい
Yessir!
I hate to say it, but Karasuno's a formidable enemy.
言いたくないけど烏野は強敵だ
I'm surprised you're being so honest.
お前が素直に言うなんて珍しいな
I learned my lesson after last time.
前回で身にしみてるからね
If we let our guard down, they'll devour us whole.
油断すれば喰われる
Let's rip them up from the get-go.
最初からブちぎていこう
Yeah!
はい/おう
All right, so, today...
よしそんじゃあ今日も
I trust...
We trust you, Captain!
信じてるぞキャプテン
You're gonna make me blu—
なんか照れる
初端のお前のサブを信じてる
We trust your serves.
If you mess up, you owe us ramen.
ミスたらラメン奢りで
I want extra roasted pork slices.
俺チャシュ大盛り
I'll add a side of potstickers to that.
俺はギョザ追加で
入れるだけサブもダメな
And lazy serves that only go over the net don't count.
ほら１２年も頼んどけ
Come on, first-years and second-years. You guys can request too.
Seriously?!
マジすか
The crow's broken wing has healed,
and now it's stronger than it's ever been.
かつて折られた翼は癒え
烏は一回りも二回りも強くなりました
この日のために鍛えてきた体と技と心を
You've trained your bodies, techniques, and minds for this day.
So please leave everything on the court, and take flight into the vast blue sky.
思う存分発揮して大空を翔けてください
As long as you do what needs to be done, the results will come your way.
やるべきことをやりさえすれば結果はついてくる
That's what I believe.
僕はそう信じています
Yes, sir!
Ukai.
鳥養くん
To be honest, Seijou's a bad match-up for you guys.
まあぶちゃけ
お前らは青城と相性が悪い
As is any team that's calm and collected.
ああいうザ柔軟性＆安定感てチムとはな
But surpassing them is our only option.
でも越えていくしかねぇ
So go win this time!
あの敗北を越えて来い
Yeah!
うおしゃぁああ
Go, go, go, go, go, Seijou!
行け行け行け行け行け青城
Rule the Court
Push it, push it, push it, push it, push it, Seijou!
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
Give us a good serve, Oikawa!
及川さんナイサ
Man, Oikawa's serving first?
初端から及川のサブかよ
Is he that good?
そんなすごいんだ
Is he?
ですか
He's a frickin' cannon.
まさに「大砲」
If Seijou's able to build momentum with his serve,
we're gonna be in trouble.
あのサブでいきなり流れ持てかれたらヤバイけど
And there's a very decent chance of that happening.
正直大いに有り得る
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
Soy sauce!
ショウユウ
トンコォツ
Pork bone!
Dan dan noodles!
担々めェん
I can't tell if you want me to land this spike or not!
決めてほしいのミスてほしいの
Sadly, there's no doubt...
残念ながらお前は
決めるに決まてる
that you're going to land it.
They were able to dig out the first serve!
１発目から上げた
All right!
よしゃ
I think just touching that would rip my arms off!
触たら腕もげそう
Wait!
でもネト越える
It's going back over the net!
They're gonna hit it down!
叩かれんぞ
Nice one, Kageyama!
影山ナイス
でも影山がファストタチ速攻はない
Kageyama touched the ball first, so they can't do a fast attack!
Their attack will be a simple...
攻撃は単調に
All right!
よしゃぁああ
Nice spike.
ナイスキ
How are those two the most surprised by it?!
決めた奴らが一番びくりしてる
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
Nice one, Asahi, Nishinoya!
ナイス旭西谷
Yeah!
Thanks!
アザス
All right, let's go,
さあ行くぜ
新生烏野
reborn Karasuno!
Give us a good serve, Kageyama!
影山ナイサ
Let's get another point!
一本
Makki!
That's a really good location!
すげぇいいコス
Shake it off!
ドンマイドンマイ
So close! You'll get the next one!
惜しいぞ次次
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
Give us a good one, Iwaizumi!
岩泉さんナイサ
I'm pretty sure his serves are intense too.
こいつのサブも強烈になてたはず
Bring it!
さ来い
Damn, it went long!
くそ長い
Sorry, Kageyama!
すまん影山
Man, there's one insane serve after another.
すげぇサブ続くな
What's with those guys?
何なんだこいつら
Hit it, Kunimi!
叩け国見
おらぁああ
Nice spike, Tanaka!
田中ナイスキ
Thanks!
サンキュ
I'm surprised he got it in!
あいつよく入てきたな
Well done, Ryuu! Love ya!
龍よくやた愛してるぜ
Stop that, Big Sis!
ちょ姉ちゃんやめろて
I wanna touch the ball too!
俺もボル触りたい
All right!
青城と烏野の試合面白ぇぞ
This Seijou vs. Karasuno match is awesome.
Oh, really?
へいどれどれ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Get another one!
もう一丁決めろィ
Nice, Mattsun.
ナイスまつん
Left!
レフト
All right!
よしゃ
もう悪
My bad!
Sorry! It was a little low!
ごめんちょと低かた
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
Give us a good serve, Tsukishima!
月島ナイサ
Go!
Wow. They're starting off neck-and-neck.
最初から互角にやり合てる
Yeah, but...
けどやぱ
I'd love to see Hinata land a fast attack right about now.
１発日向に速攻決めてほしいとこだなぁ
Yeah.
確かにな
Why?
なんで
At the end of their last match with Seijou,
前回の青城戦のラスト
Hinata's fast attack had the perfect timing, but it still got completely shut down.
完璧なタイミングだた日向の速攻が
ドシャト喰らて終わたんだ
It even left an impression on us.
俺達もアレは印象に残てるからな
Give us another good serve!
For Hinata and Kageyama, it might not be a memory they can just sweep away.
日向と影山には拭い切れない一本なんじゃねぇかな
ナイサいこう
岩ちゃん
Iwa!
Nice, Daichi!
大地さんナイス
Here it comes!
来た
Yes! He was perfectly positioned!
よしいいとこいた
It's coming back over! Move back! Back!
返てくる下がれ下がれ
Cover it!
He's so worked up that he didn't see the block!
こいつ熱くなりすぎてブロク見えてねぇな
Damn it. I'll get the next one!
Nice one, Oikawa!
クソ次
及川さんナイス
Calm don't... up... down, moron!
冷静にし
いやなれボケェ
What was that?
日本語
That goes for you too, Kageyama.
影山お前もな
We're counting on you, Iwaizumi!
岩泉さんお願いします
Damn it. He kicked me for real!
クソ影山思いきり蹴りやがて
Yeah!
ナイスワンチ
Nice contact!
もかいもかい
Keep it going!
Got it!
オライ
One more time!
もう一回
Go!
行け
Use our despair...
あの絶望の一本を
to smash through!
ぶ壊せ
これで
We're finally...
at the start line!
スタトラインだ
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
That number ten is awesome!
あの１０番すげぇ
Karasuno's really good this year.
今年の烏野やぱ強ぇな
All right!
おしゃ
Nice spike, Hinata!
日向ナイスキ
That's it, Hinata!
いいぞ日向
We're finally...
これでスタトラインだ
at the start line!
思いきり蹴りやがてこのヤロウ
You kicked me for real, you jerk!
I woke you up, moron!
目覚ましてやたんだろがボケェ
What'd you say?!
Now, now...
Damn. They've picked themselves back up.
復活しやがた
But that's only thanks to my advice!
まあ俺のアドバイスのおかげだけどな
Those two getting more confident is hardly a good thing.
あのコンビ調子付かせると厄介だぞ
I know.
分かてるよ
焦らずじくり攻略していこうか
Let's take our time and form a strategy.
Yeah!
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
まだ１セト目だけど青城相手にこのスコアはすげぇよ
This is only the first set,
but that's an impressive score against Seijou.
Yeah.
烏野まさかここまでやるとは思わなかた
I didn't think Karasuno would make it this far.
前回のはまぐれじゃなかたんだな
I guess their performance last time wasn't just a fluke.
All right!
よしゃあ
Nice receive, Daichi!
大地さんナイスレシブ
Are they not going to try to block Hinata's broad jump again?
今回も日向のブロドにはレシブだけで対応か
All right!
よしゃあ
ナイス日向
Nice, Hinata!
It looks like where number ten
hit it last time wasn't an accident.
あの１０番のコス打ち分けはやぱりまぐれじゃないんだ
Shake it off!
ドンマイドンマイ
Give us a good serve, Kageyama!
影山ナイサ
すいませんカバ
Sorry! Someone get under it!
We're counting on you, Makki!
マキ頼むよ
あいよ
Got it!
Kunimi!
国見
Right!
ナイスキ
Nice spike!
ナイストスです
Nice set.
They did that like it was nothing.
こういうことさらとやりやがてうめぇなクソが
They're so damn good.
Aoba Jousai always plays so skillfully.
相変わらず青葉城西の熟練感というか
How well their gears mesh together is truly impressive.
歯車の噛み合い方は素晴らしい
岩泉ナイサ
Give us a good one, Iwaizumi!
Yeah, it really pisses me off!
ああ腹立つわ
Sorry!
All right!
よしゃあ
すまん
Karasuno                       Aoba Jousai
Yeah!
よしゃあ
マキナイスキ
Nice spike, Makki!
お願いします
We're counting on you.
Hey.
おいちょと
Bring it!
さあ来い
The guys who don't do jump serves aim for...
ジャンプサブ以外のやつが狙て来んのは
Got it!
オライ
It's time for the back row setter to make his appearance!
来た後衛セタの出てくる場所
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
Yes! Nice and clean!
よし綺麗に上がた
Go for another broad jump, Hinata!
日向もう一発ブロド行け
He's going in for the block?
ブロクつくのか
１枚で止めるのはしんどい
It'll be hard to stop it by myself...
こちには打たないでね打てないよね
Please don't hit it over here, okay?
You can't hit it this way, right?
Here it is!
来たストレト真正面
A straight spike right at me!
お前はクロス無視してストレトで待てな
You ignore the cross-court spike and wait for a straight spike.
金田一ナイスレシブ
Nice receive, Kindaichi!
They forced him to the side!
コス絞らされた
Counterattack!
カウンタ
All right!
よしゃあ
He put me under so much pressure.
すげぇプレシャやぱ３年生怖ぇ
Those third-years are scary!
Nice receive, Kindaichi!
ナイスレシブ金田一
Thanks!
あざす
Looks like if we cut off his options, then we can dig out the spike.
うまいことコス絞れば拾えるな
I'll give it a shot next time.
俺も次やてみます
You're pretty scary right now, Mattsun.
まつん怖ぇ
Shake it off, Shouyou! You almost had it!
ドンマイ翔陽惜しかたぞ
They've already thought up a way to counter Hinata's broad jump.
さそく日向のブロドの対抗策を考えてきやがた
Right!
Nothing less from Seijou.
さすがだな青城
Indeed.
They're always thinking as they play.
常に選手一人一人が考えてプレしてる
That's probably why they're so good.
それが青城の強さの源なんだろうな
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
But...
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
Sugawara told me that with Seijou's fast attacks,
I should wait a little while...
菅原さんが言てた
青城の速攻はいつもより少しタイミング溜めてから
跳ぶ
and then jump!
All right!
しゃあ
How's payback taste?
お返しだぜ
Don't get so cocky after just one point!
一本で調子乗んなや
よし前回の経験ちゃんと活きてる
Good!
He learned from last time!
烏野の対応力上がてますね
Karasuno's able to handle us a lot better this go-round.
We can't seem to pull ahead.
どうにもあと一歩乗り切れない
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
Great, great, Yuutarou! Push it, push it, Yuutarou!
Do it again!
Rule the Court
Here he comes again.
さあまた回てきたぞ
It's the guy whose serve could rip your arm off.
腕もげサブの人
Give us a good serve, Oikawa!
及川ナイサ
Just in case, watch the back of your head.
一応後頭部気をつけろよ
What?
さ来い
Bring it!
ごめん
Sorry!
Damn it!
チクショウ
惜しいナイス攻めサブ
So close! I like the aggressiveness, though!
Let's get the next one!
次次
That was lucky!
ラキラキもう一本取ろう
Let's get another point!
はあ何だ今の
Huh?! What the hell was that?!
He can hit the ball even harder?!
まだ威力上げてくんのかよ
ほぼスパイクじゃねぇか
That was basically a spike!
今のけこう手応え良かたんだけどな
That felt pretty good against my hand.
たまたまあの威力だたのか
Maybe that serve was a fluke.
Get over it!
No, it wasn't a fluke.
切り替え
いやまぐれとは違う違う気がする
Got it!
ウィス
At least, I don't think it was.
Did he hit it that hard knowing it was risky?
意図的にリスクを犯してても威力を上げた
すげぇサブだたな取てみてぇ
That was an insane serve!
I wanna try to receive it!
What a sound...
I can't... Someone's arms are gonna fly off...
もう腕吹き飛んじゃう
正直俺も取れる気しねぇ
Honestly, I don't think I could get that myself.
気がついたらこちにバウンドしてたて感じだな
Feels like it hit the ground before I even noticed.
But...
Karasuno                    Aoba Jousai
おし先にセトポイント
All right!
We're at set point!
Just one more!
後１点一気に取れ
Go for it!
Thanks.
あざす
簡単に超えられるなんて思てねぇ
It won't be easy to surpass that serve.
I shouldn't try too hard to compete.
張り合て力むな
６人で強いほうが強いんだ
The team does better when we all play well.
Whoa, is Karasuno really going to take the first set?
おいおいマジで烏野が１セト目取ちまうぞ
Seijou better think of something fast,
or they might be in trouble.
青城何か対策立てないとやべぇんじゃねえのかこれ
We're gonna take this set!
このセト取るぞ凌いでけよ
Keep it up!
Right!
ウス/はい
恐れている暇はない勝負に出なくてはね
This is no time to panic.
They need to go out there and fight.
Nice spike, Iwaizumi!
Karasuno                       Aoba Jousai
岩泉ナイスキ
If Seijou scores one more point, it'll be a deuce.
青城後１点取ればデュスか
They'll lose if they don't.
ブレクするしかないな
落ち着いて一本
Stay calm! Just one point to go!
We're gonna score here!
一本確実に取てくぞ
Right!
Just one more point,
and we can take the first set off of Seijou!
後１点で青城から第１セト取れる
Focus on this point!
一本集中
Trying to get that last point can be rough.
こういう一本が一番きついんだよな
True, but Seijou's got it even harder.
まあなでも青城のほうが更にきつい
Seijou's swapping players?
青城ここでメンバチェンジ
This is where it happens?
ここでですか
It's that guy from earlier.
さきのあいつだ
Yeah.
I've never seen that player before.
初めて見る選手だな
Yes.
He's not a pinch server or anything,
ピンチサバでもないのに
and yet they're putting him in for the first time when their opponent is at set point?
敵にセトポイント握られているこのタイミングで
初めてコトに出すなんて
They might be strengthening their blocking on the left side.
レフト側のブロクの強化かもしれん
Make sure your spikes don't get blocked.
スパイク捕まらないように注意な
Yessir.
Give us a good serve, Iwaizumi!
岩泉さんナイサ
すまん短い
Sorry, it's short!
田中さん
Tanaka!
ワンチ
I touched it!
Let's score here!
チャンスボル
Got it!
オライ
Kindaichi...
金田一
綺麗すぎるほどに噛み合ていた歯車を
A wrench was intentionally thrown into the gears that were working together flawlessly.
自ら狂わせる
途端それは得体の知れないものとなる
Then suddenly, they became something completely mysterious and unknown.
なんかぐわドカンてスパイクでしたよねあの１６番
Number sixteen's spike was all "whoosh" and "boom"!
でもよ目つきの悪さといい挑発的な態度といい
I have to wonder why he's playing volleyball, considering how evil his eyes look and how provocative he is.
バレボラとしてどうかと思うぜ
All of that applies to you too, you know.
田中それ全部お前にも当てはまてる
Episode Twenty-one:
The Destroyer
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ壊し屋
"The Destroyer."